<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <string name="app_name">ShardQuorum</string>
    <string name="home_tagline">Split a secret into shards. A quorum reconstructs it.</string>
    <string name="home_create">Create a new secret</string>
    <string name="home_recover">Recover from shards</string>
    <string name="home_about">How it works</string>

    <string name="onboarding_skip">Skip</string>
    <string name="onboarding_next">Next</string>
    <string name="onboarding_done">Get started</string>

    <string name="onboarding_1_title">Split a secret into shards</string>
    <string name="onboarding_1_body">A shard is a piece of your secret - like a key fragment. ShardQuorum splits your secret so that a certain number of shards (the quorum) must be brought together to unlock it. Fewer than that reveal nothing.\n\nAll work happens on this device, entirely offline. Nothing is ever sent to the internet.</string>

    <string name="onboarding_2_title">Creating a secret</string>
    <string name="onboarding_2_body">Give your secret a label, then type or paste it in. Pick how many shards to create and how many are needed to unlock it (the quorum).\n\nThe app shows you each shard one at a time - save or share them separately. Store them in different places with different people so no single place holds enough to reach the quorum.</string>

    <string name="onboarding_3_title">Recovering your secret</string>
    <string name="onboarding_3_body">When you need the secret back, gather enough shards to reach the quorum. Scan their QR codes, type the words, or import saved files.\n\nAdd the recovery envelope that came with each shard - it is needed to unlock an encrypted secret. Once the quorum is met, your secret is shown.</string>

    <string name="about_title">How ShardQuorum works</string>
    <string name="about_intro">ShardQuorum protects a single high-value secret - a password-manager passphrase, a crypto wallet seed, a disk-encryption key - by splitting it into pieces called shards. You decide how many shards exist and how many are needed to rebuild the secret. The app works entirely offline and never touches the internet.</string>

    <string name="about_sss_heading">Shamir\'s Secret Sharing</string>
    <string name="about_sss_body">The idea behind ShardQuorum is Shamir\'s Secret Sharing. It splits your secret into a number of shards (N) and sets a quorum (K). Any K shards rebuild the secret exactly. Any K minus 1 or fewer reveal nothing at all - not part of the secret, not even a hint. This is a mathematical guarantee, not just a hard puzzle.\n\nA common choice is 3-of-5: five shards exist, any three rebuild the secret. You could lose two shards, or have two fall into the wrong hands, and your secret stays both recoverable and safe.</string>

    <string name="about_sskr_heading">How shards are stored</string>
    <string name="about_sskr_body">Each shard is encoded using SSKR (Sharded Secret Key Reconstruction), an open standard from Blockchain Commons. A shard can be kept two ways:\n\n• As a QR code, for quick scanning.\n• As a short list of plain English words, easy to write on paper by hand.\n\nBoth carry the same information. The words include a built-in checksum, so a typo is caught before it can cause trouble.</string>

    <string name="about_envelope_heading">The recovery envelope</string>
    <string name="about_envelope_body">By default your secret travels with the shards as an encrypted recovery envelope. Keep a copy of the envelope alongside every shard. The shards unlock the envelope; on their own, neither the shards nor the envelope reveal anything.</string>

    <string name="about_use_heading">Using the app</string>
    <string name="about_use_create">Create. Tap “Create a new secret”, give it a vague name, type or paste your secret, and choose your quorum (K) and number of shards (N). The app generates the shards and shows them one at a time.</string>
    <string name="about_use_distribute">Distribute. Save or share each shard separately, and store them in different places with different people - a fireproof box at home, a trusted relative, a bank safe-deposit box. No single place should hold enough shards to reach the quorum.</string>
    <string name="about_use_verify">Verify. Before you rely on them, the app asks you to re-enter a quorum of shards to prove they really do rebuild the secret. Do not skip this step.</string>
    <string name="about_use_recover">Recover. When you need the secret back, tap “Recover from shards” and add a quorum of them by scanning QR codes, typing the words, or importing a saved file.</string>

    <string name="about_safety_heading">Staying safe</string>
    <string name="about_safety_body">Send each shard a different way. If one app, account, or person ends up holding enough shards, they can rebuild your secret on their own.\n\nWhen the secret is split or rebuilt, the phone briefly sees the whole thing. ShardQuorum protects your secret while it is stored and distributed, not while it is in use - so do this on a device you trust. The screen also blocks screenshots while shards are shown.</string>

    <string name="about_interop_heading">Will other apps work?</string>
    <string name="about_interop_body">Your shards use SSKR, an open standard, so other SSKR-compatible tools can read and recombine them. But recombining recovers only the random key, not your secret - the encrypted envelope that holds the secret is ShardQuorum\'s own format, and other tools cannot open it. So for recovery that never depends on this app, keep the contents of the Recovery Kit stored alongside each shard.</string>

    <string name="about_quantum_heading">Is my secret safe from quantum computers?</string>
    <string name="about_quantum_body">Yes. Quantum computers threaten public-key cryptography - the kind used in web browsing and digital signatures. ShardQuorum uses none of it.\n\nThe splitting math, Shamir\'s Secret Sharing, is information-theoretically secure: fewer than a quorum of shards contain no information about the secret, so there is nothing for any computer - quantum or otherwise - to compute.\n\nThe recovery envelope is sealed with AES-256, a symmetric cipher. The best known quantum attack (Grover\'s algorithm) would at most halve its effective strength to 128 bits, which is still far beyond any foreseeable attack. So an adversary who copies your shards or envelope today, hoping to decrypt them later, gains nothing when quantum computers arrive.</string>

    <string name="about_back">Back</string>

    <string name="recover_title">Recover secret</string>
    <string name="recover_progress_empty">Add your first shard to begin.</string>
    <string name="recover_progress">Collected %1$d of %2$d shards needed</string>
    <string name="recover_shard_imported">Shard imported</string>
    <string name="recover_shard_chip">Shard %1$d (tap to remove)</string>
    <string name="recover_envelope_added">Recovery envelope added</string>
    <string name="recover_clear_envelope">Remove</string>
    <string name="recover_method_words">Type words</string>
    <string name="recover_method_scan">Scan QR</string>
    <string name="recover_method_file">Import file</string>
    <string name="recover_word_help">Type the words printed under a shard\'s QR code, separated by spaces.</string>
    <string name="recover_word_label">Shard words</string>
    <string name="recover_word_unknown">“%1$s” is not a valid word.</string>
    <string name="recover_word_suggest">“%1$s” is not a valid word - did you mean: %2$s?</string>
    <string name="recover_add_shard">Add shard</string>
    <string name="recover_scan_help">Point the camera at a shard\'s QR code - it is added automatically. Scan each shard and the recovery envelope QR.</string>
    <string name="recover_scan_start">Start camera</string>
    <string name="recover_scan_close">Close camera</string>
    <string name="recover_camera_rationale">Camera access is used only to scan shard QR codes, on-device. It is never required - you can also type words or import a file.</string>
    <string name="recover_camera_grant">Grant camera access</string>
    <string name="recover_file_help">Import a saved shard file: a QR image (PNG) or a saved words text file.</string>
    <string name="recover_pick_file">Choose file</string>
    <string name="recover_file_decoding">Reading and decoding the image…</string>
    <string name="recover_button">Recover secret</string>
    <string name="recover_error_unrecognized">Not a recognized shard or envelope.</string>
    <string name="recover_error_different_split">That shard belongs to a different secret (different split identifier). Remove it and use only shards from the same set.</string>
    <string name="recover_error_duplicate">That shard was already added.</string>
    <string name="recover_error_not_enough">Add more shards to reach the quorum.</string>
    <string name="recover_error_failed">These shards do not combine into a valid secret. They may be wrong, too few, or damaged.</string>
    <string name="recover_error_envelope">The shards combined, but the recovery envelope is wrong, missing, or damaged.</string>
    <string name="recover_error_image_decode">Could not find a QR code in that image. Try a clearer photo or type the words instead.</string>

    <string name="verify_title">Verify your shards</string>
    <string name="verify_instructions">Re-enter any %1$d shards the way recipients will - scan a QR, type the words, or import a file - to prove they rebuild this secret before you distribute them.</string>
    <string name="verify_progress">Re-entered %1$d of %2$d needed</string>
    <string name="verify_ok">Verified - these shards rebuild your secret.</string>
    <string name="verify_mismatch">These shards do NOT rebuild the secret. Re-check what you saved, then try again.</string>
    <string name="verify_error_different_split">That shard is from a different secret (different split identifier). Use only shards generated together.</string>
    <string name="verify_finish">Finish</string>
    <string name="verify_skip">Skip verification</string>
    <string name="verify_skip_title">Skip verification?</string>
    <string name="verify_skip_message">Without verifying, you cannot be sure your saved shards actually rebuild the secret. If any were mis-saved, the secret may be lost. Skip anyway?</string>
    <string name="verify_skip_confirm">Skip and finish</string>
    <string name="verify_skip_cancel">Go back</string>

    <string name="recovered_title">Recovered secret</string>
    <string name="recovered_warning">Shown only while this screen is open. It is not saved.</string>
    <string name="recovered_maybe_encrypted">This may be an encrypted secret\'s key, not the secret itself. Add a recovery envelope to decrypt it.</string>
    <string name="recovered_add_envelope">Add recovery envelope</string>
    <string name="recovered_done">Done</string>

    <string name="create_title">New secret</string>
    <string name="create_name_label">Secret name</string>
    <string name="create_name_warning">Shown on every shard - anyone who has or finds one can read it, so keep it vague.</string>
    <string name="create_secret_label_text">Your secret</string>
    <string name="create_secret_placeholder">e.g. your password manager passphrase</string>
    <string name="create_secret_supporting">Never stored or sent anywhere. All work happens on this device.</string>
    <string name="create_threshold_label">Quorum (K): %1$d</string>
    <string name="create_share_count_label">Shards (N): %1$d</string>
    <string name="create_scheme_summary">Any %1$d of %2$d shards reconstruct the secret. Fewer reveal nothing.</string>
    <string name="create_preset_3of5">3 of 5 shards (recommended)</string>
    <string name="create_preset_3of5_desc">Lose up to 2. Safe against 2 stolen.</string>
    <string name="create_preset_5of7">5 of 7 shards</string>
    <string name="create_preset_5of7_desc">Lose up to 2. Safe against 4 stolen.</string>
    <string name="create_preset_custom">Custom…</string>
    <string name="create_generate">Generate shards</string>
    <string name="create_continue_verify">Continue to verify</string>
    <string name="create_error_name_required">A name is required.</string>
    <string name="create_error_secret_required">Enter the secret to protect.</string>
    <string name="create_error_secret_too_long">The secret is too long. Maximum is %1$d bytes (some characters use several bytes).</string>

    <string name="shard_showing">Showing shard %1$d of %2$d</string>
    <string name="shard_page_scheme">Any %1$d of %2$d shards reconstruct the secret</string>
    <string name="shard_qr_description">QR code of this shard</string>
    <string name="shard_nav_prev">Previous</string>
    <string name="shard_nav_next">Next</string>
    <string name="shard_abandon_title">Leave without finishing?</string>
    <string name="shard_abandon_message">These shards are shown only once and will be discarded. You will need to start over. Leave anyway?</string>
    <string name="shard_abandon_yes">Discard and leave</string>
    <string name="shard_abandon_no">Keep going</string>
    <string name="shard_save">Save…</string>
    <string name="shard_saved_progress">Saved %1$d of %2$d</string>
    <string name="shard_save_title">Save this shard</string>
    <string name="shard_save_kit">Save recovery kit (ZIP)</string>
    <string name="shard_save_kit_subtitle">This shard plus the offline recovery tool and spec. Recommended.</string>
    <string name="shard_save_qr">Save QR image only (PNG)</string>
    <string name="shard_save_words">Save words only (text)</string>
    <string name="shard_save_cancel">Cancel</string>
    <string name="png_label_shard">Shard %1$d of %2$d</string>
    <string name="png_label_envelope">Recovery envelope</string>
    <string name="shard_envelope_heading">Recovery envelope</string>
    <string name="shard_envelope_explanation">Keep a copy of this envelope with every shard. Shards alone cannot recover the secret; the envelope alone reveals nothing.</string>
    <string name="shard_envelope_qr_description">QR code of the encrypted recovery envelope</string>
</resources>
